What happens when the numbers run out?
Knowing is a action, mystery, science fiction film directed by Alex Proyas.
A teacher opens a time capsule that has been dug up at his son's elementary school; in it are some chilling predictions -- some that have already
occurred and others that are about to -- that lead him to believe his family plays a role in the events that are about to unfold.
John Koestler, played by Nicolas Cage.
Diana Wayland, played by Rose Byrne.
Caleb Koestler, played by Chandler Canterbury.
Phil Bergman, played by Ben Mendelsohn.
Grace Koestler, played by Nadia Townsend.
Cashier, played by Terry Camilleri.
Knowing (stylized as KNOW1NG) is a 2009 science fiction thriller film
directed and co-produced by Alex Proyas and starring Nicolas Cage.
The film, conceived and co-written by Ryne Douglas Pearson, was originally attached to a number of directors
under Columbia Pictures, but it was placed in turnaround and eventually picked up by Escape Artists.
Production was financially backed by Summit Entertainment.
Knowing was filmed in Docklands Studios Melbourne, Australia, using
various locations to represent the film's Boston-area setting.
The film centers on the discovery of a strange paper filled with numbers and the
possibility that they somehow predict the details of various disasters.
The film was released on March 20, 2009, in the United States.
The DVD and Blu-ray media were released on July 7.
Knowing grossed $186.5 million at the worldwide box office, plus $27.7 million with
home video sales, against an average production budget of $50 million.
It met with mixed reviews, with praise for the acting performances, visual style and
atmosphere, but criticism over some implausibilities and the ending.
The film explores themes of cataclysm, melancholy, code, alien, time capsule.
The tone is mind_bending and thought_provoking and intense.